<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-11-27T17:45:18+00:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Too much coffee, too little time</title><subtitle>Ivan De Marino&apos;s blog and personal website</subtitle><author><name>Ivan De Marino</name></author><entry><title type="html">Ugly, expensive Housing</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2015/07/ugly-expensive-housing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ugly, expensive Housing" /><published>2015-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2015/07/ugly-expensive-housing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2015/07/ugly-expensive-housing"><![CDATA[<p>Yet <a href="/2015/07/HTB-means-richer-builders/">another</a> take on expensive housing.</p>

<p>I’m not sure I fully agree with the idea that poor aesthetic (actually, <em>ugliness</em>)
has a dominating role in the pricing bubble. I still believe the the biggest issue
is with political choices, that most probably are driven by lobbist interests.</p>

<p>Nevertheless this video is an interesting and watch-worth perspective.</p>

<div class="img">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dcbjWGj3jBk?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>After watching this video I subscribed to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC7IcJI8PUf5Z3zKxnZvTBog">“The School of Life”</a>
channel. And frankly you should too.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ivan De Marino</name></author><category term="help to buy" /><category term="uk" /><category term="politics" /><category term="housing" /><category term="bubble" /><category term="pricing" /><category term="ugly" /><category term="expensive" /><category term="aesthetic" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yet another take on expensive housing.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Help to Buy means richer Builders</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2015/07/HTB-means-richer-builders" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Help to Buy means richer Builders" /><published>2015-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2015/07/HTB-means-richer-builders</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2015/07/HTB-means-richer-builders"><![CDATA[<p>Britain, you have a problem: house prices in the East/South East have grown
ridiculous. See
<a href="http://www.ons.gov.uk/ons/rel/hpi/house-price-index/april-2014/info-hpi-comparison.html">2014 house pricing data by the Office for National Statistics (ONS)</a> that compares prices
with the pre-crisis ones.</p>

<div class="img">
    <img src="http://www.ons.gov.uk/ons/resources/hpifinal_tcm77-369630.png" alt="Comparison of Regional House Prices Indices BEFORE and AFTER the Financial Crisis (2014)" />
    <span>+31.6!?!?!?!</span>
</div>

<p>We all know that UK is very much London centered, and this is reflected in the
graph above. The government doesn’t shy away from policy that are openly “pro-London”
and while there are complaints, as an immigrant since 2007, I can see not much
more than some “grumpiness” about it. It’s like Britons are <em>“sort of ok with it”</em>.</p>

<h2 id="enter-help-to-buy-scheme">Enter “Help to Buy” scheme</h2>

<p>To address the housing needs, the Tory government has come up with <a href="http://www.helptobuy.org.uk/">Help to Buy</a>: you put 5% deposit (say £10k), the government puts 20% (say £40k) and you can now afford a home of up to £200k - you can easily find a bank that would give you
a Mortgage for <strong>75% LTV</strong>. It’s like asking them for a glass of water: of course
they will have you as a customer.</p>

<p>This sounds great, but it’s actually a recipe for disaster.</p>

<h2 id="can-i-buy-any-kind-of-home-with-the-htb-scheme">Can I buy any kind of home with the HTB scheme?</h2>

<p>HTB has been launched in 2 phases in 2013: <strong>HTB1</strong> (<em>Equity Loan</em>) and <strong>HTB2</strong> (<em>Mortgage Guarantees</em>) first only applied for newly built homes,
now HTB can be used also to purchase pre-built homes. But ONLY in the formula HTB2:
instead of giving you 20% of the money, the HTB2 just makes the government guarantor
of your Mortgage.</p>

<p>All of those, capped to £600k.</p>

<p>Sounds good, right?
Not a bit. But first let’s highlight the benefit.</p>

<h2 id="so-why-everyone-is-buying-so-much-if-htb-is-so-bad">So, why everyone is buying so much if HTB is so bad?</h2>

<p>Because we are stupid. Humans rarely think long term.
All of a sudden, Bob (fictional character) can afford a much bigger house, and he
has to only provide 5% of deposit. Suddenly, life is amazing.</p>

<p>HTB works as a loan: once you buy, you are repaying the government a monthly installment
(to define with a HMRC official). First 5 years are interest free (WOW!) and then
it’s like 1.5% + some increase over time. It’s a great loan compared to any Mortgage.</p>

<p>If prices of houses were fair, this would be a great thing that would really
allow people to buy a home.</p>

<h2 id="beyond-their-means">Beyond their means</h2>

<p>In short, people are buying beyond their means.
Yes, you have taken 20% of the money with this great cheap loan, so in theory you
are saving loads of money. But still, you now have 2 loans: a Mortgage and the HTB loan.
Your credit score is affected. You are less “trust worthy” in case you need an emergency
loan.</p>

<p>And if that 5% deposit was already hard to put together, you are most certainly now
in a situation where ALL your income is taken by the repayments.
You can make it, but just a glitch in your monthly INs/OUTs and you are in trouble.</p>

<p>I have made my calculation, so it’s possible to take the HTB and still be comfortably
between your means. But as a Software Engineer, my income is way above the national
average: I ought to be in this position.</p>

<h2 id="builders-are-getting-richer-at-tax-payers-expenses">Builders are getting richer, at tax-payers expenses</h2>

<p>If house prices where a fixed value, this whole HTB thing would be great and Britain
would have no housing problems.</p>

<p>But the market laws are well known: flood the market with money, and prices will soar.
And that’s what’s happening. House prices are going drastically up because more people
can afford them all of a sudden.</p>

<p>That would be “OK” if there wasn’t a party exploiting this.</p>

<p>What we forget to consider, is that Government’s Money is OUR money. Is what every
month we pay in taxes. Is the the 20/30/40/50% of our monthly sweat that goes “puff”
so that the <em>“Government Machine can keep cranking”</em>. Mind you, I’m not complaining
about this: this is what a government does - takes money from X to make Y happen.
It’s sort-of an investment logic at play, on a country-scale.</p>

<p>The issue I have is that the HTB is being exploited BIG TIME by big house builders
(i.e. not your average tiny builder - we are talking about market-floating companies like
<a href="http://www.bewley.co.uk/">Bewley Homes</a>, <a href="http://www.barratthomes.co.uk/">Barrat / David Wilson</a>, <a href="https://bloorhomes.com/">Bloor Homes</a>, <a href="https://www.crestnicholson.com/">Crest Nicholson</a>…)
to squeeze as much money as possible out of buyers and government’s pocket. That
at the end of the day are the same pocket!</p>

<p>And how they do that? How they maximise their profit? <strong>Withholding properties!</strong></p>

<p>Try to go to any site where they have set up a show-room and they are starting
to sell the first plots. They will tell you that “only this much are available right now”.
You will ask “what’s going to be available in X months?”. They will show you what
but prices will not be available because, in X months, the very same house, built 50
meters down the same road, might be able to go on the market for £10/20k extra!</p>

<p>New homes increase the market-demand for homes. Even pre-owned. This is basic
economics that any university student has studied at some point. It’s called
“Fabricated Demand”. You go down the street, and see signage of “New Luxury Homes” in
your neighbourhood. Your mind now wants to buy, but the new homes are too costly.
So you buy something else.</p>

<p>The houses on the market reduce in number, so what’s left can ask for more money.
The builder knows that the customer can use HTB to “spend that little extra for their
dream home”. So they are ready to release houses at the right time. At a price that
maximise profit.</p>

<p>To prove that, check the price of homes that are above the HTB £600k threshold:
because HTB doesn’t apply to them, their prices can’t move as much. They incur the
risk of going “out of market”.</p>

<h2 id="whats-different-from-the-usual-market-rules">What’s different from the usual “market rules”</h2>

<p>What’s different is that the HTB has injected money that have altered reality.
More money means pushing prices beyond the “too expensive” point. The point that
houses were supposed to reach, before demand will cease and sellers would be forced
to rethink their pricing.</p>

<p>Ah, and consider also that UK has done massive <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantitative_easing">Quantitative Easing (QE)</a>: pretty much printing money.
This is where the Government gets the extra-edge to support HTB.</p>

<p>But QE is a dangerous thing to over-use: ultimately those extra money in the market
will be paid by the tax-payers, through massively inflated prices (i.e. <em>inflation baby!</em>).</p>

<h2 id="what-happens-once-you-cant-repay-your-mortgage">What happens once you can’t repay your Mortgage?</h2>

<p><strong>Who cares! The builder is happy!</strong> Who is in trouble is the customer (that can’t
repay the mortgage and loses his/her home) and the Government (that has lost
tax-payers money).</p>

<p>In this game, the loser is always you.
Unless you are a builder: in that case your third yacht is coming next week.</p>

<p><strong>I’d call this ++a new house bubble++.</strong> But in a country where media are very much influenced by
government, mentioning bubble would probably get journalists fired…</p>]]></content><author><name>Ivan De Marino</name></author><category term="help to buy" /><category term="uk" /><category term="politics" /><category term="affordable" /><category term="housing" /><category term="bubble" /><category term="pricing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Britain, you have a problem: house prices in the East/South East have grown ridiculous. See 2014 house pricing data by the Office for National Statistics (ONS) that compares prices with the pre-crisis ones.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Phonebooth on Mount Sinai</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2014/02/phonebooth-on-mount-sinai" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Phonebooth on Mount Sinai" /><published>2014-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2014/02/phonebooth-on-mount-sinai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2014/02/phonebooth-on-mount-sinai"><![CDATA[<p>Moses didn’t know what to do any more with those idiots. So he decides to go
out for a wander. The pressure was too much. He knew that, sooner or later,
they will just crash his skull with a stone. He needed a plan. He needed a way
to survive (both him and them!), without ruining it all. Without having to look
the fool he knew he was.</p>

<div class="img">
    <img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/be/Mount_Sinai_Egypt.jpg/800px-Mount_Sinai_Egypt.jpg" />
    <span>Mount Sinai, Egypt</span>
</div>

<p>To cool off, he decides to go up there. On that peak no one will follow him.
They were all pretty much exhausted: no sane mind would follow him in a hike at
this stage. Good, that would do!</p>

<p>Also, on top of that no stupid idiot would yell at him how stupid was to leave
the stupid Egyptians. Yes, slavery was bad, and building palaces, pyramids and
the sort was getting boring, but they got something to eat there. A shelter.
A mean to survive.</p>

<p>When he is about to reach the top of the mountain, from far, he sees something
“sparkly”. A big metal box, looking like made of gold, but was too far to
distinguish it’s details. So, he decided to look into it.</p>

<div class="img">
    <img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/10/Lightmatter_phonebooths.jpg" />
    <span>"THE" Phonebooth</span>
</div>

<p>Unbelievable! It was a… phonebooth. No keypad on it: just one button.
On the button and engraved on it: <strong>“Mr God”</strong>.</p>

<p>He picks the phone, pushes the button and waits…</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in Heaven.</p>

<p>(Phone ringing)</p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Mmm…</em></p>

<p>(Phone still ringing)</p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Oh crap! Another idiot calling from Sinai. I don’t have time for this shit today!</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>God, do you want me to take that?</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Yes, please. Tell him to fuck off.</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>OK!</em></p>

<p>Secretary (whispering)&gt; <em>Such a tool…</em></p>

<p>(Secretary answers the phone)</p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>Heeeelllo!</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Hi. Is this God?</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>Actually, I’m his secretary. Farrokh.</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Farrokh?</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>Yes, Farrokh. Farrokh Bulsara.</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>You are a man! I would assumed God’s secretary to be a hot girl</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>You haven’t seen me, my dear!</em></p>

<p>(Awkward silence)</p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>So, how can I help?</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>May I speak with Mr God, please.</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>God is quite busy at the moment. He is working on his latest play: “Landing in America”.</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Mmm… OK. Whatever. Can I speak with him?</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>He is actually very busy. He hates being interrupted when he is testing new religious scenarios.</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>It will only take a minute!</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>Mmm… wait please.</em></p>

<p>(Secretary puts his hand on the phone and starts whispering to God)</p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>He insists. He sounds quite like a rude guy. Do you want me to put him through?</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>FUCK!!! I’m never gonna finish this shit if I get interrupted all the time!</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>OK. Let the fucker through. But fucking cut the line if I’m not done in 2 minutes.
Those South Americans can’t be kept waiting. They already started building all
sort of crazy shit to substitute me and I got to crash that pretty soon…</em></p>

<p>(God coughs and deepens his voice)</p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Hello child!</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Hello God. How have you been?</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Moses! It’s been a while. Did you like the water trick?</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Impressive. For a second I thought you won’t be paying attention and I’d
have looked like a tool, standing there with my harms in the air, and nothing
actually happening.</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Glad to be helpful.</em></p>

<p>(God picking his nose while talking)</p>

<p>God&gt; <em>OK. It was nice to speak with you. I shall…</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Wait. I called to ask for your help. Those people down there, they are driving me crazy!</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>One of them just started melting gold and he wants to make a cow! Or a Lamb, I don’t know.</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Yes, I have seen it - I won’t worry too much. You will probably be all dead pretty soon…</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>But they want to worship it!!!</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Stupid dick-heads! That’s why I’m giving up on y’all!</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>“Y’all”!?!?!</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Yeah. I started to pick up some of that American slang you know…</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>No please. I need your help! Don’t you have an advice or a message I could bring to them?</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Shit. I’m tired. It has been a long day. Can’t you call again tomorrow?</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Come on! You are usually so patronising? For once that I’m actually asking for it?</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Mmmm… OK. Have you got a pen?</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>No. Left it in the other trousers. I got a couple of stone slabs though…</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>That would do!</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>OK. Go ahead!</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>First Commandment: <strong>NEVER CALL GOD IN VANE!</strong>
He is a cranky old man and he can’t really hear you anyway.
He is busy having fun torturing minions all the time and no interest in helping them.
So, leave him alone. Unless you are a hot gay version of David Jude Heyworth Law.</em></p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Oh. OK. That’s it?</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Of course not, fuck face. Here is number Two.</em></p>

<p>(Click. Phone disconnects.)</p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>God? GOD? Holy shit, this guy! He is impossible.</em></p>

<p>(Moses thinks a bit and then says…)</p>

<p>Moses&gt; <em>Well, once again, I suppose I’ll have to just make stuff up.</em></p>

<p>(Meanwhile)</p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Moses? MOSES? Whatever…</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>I cut the line. As you asked.</em></p>

<p>God&gt; <em>Oh! It was YOU then. Well done. You are my saviour, as usual.</em></p>

<p>Secretary&gt; <em>My pleasure <a href="http://youtu.be/lBhPDxszukU" target="_blank">Brian</a>.
Please go back to your plays now: those plagues are not going to make themselves.</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Ivan De Marino</name></author><category term="satire" /><category term="sinai" /><category term="phonebooth" /><category term="god" /><category term="moses" /><category term="phonecall" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moses didn’t know what to do any more with those idiots. So he decides to go out for a wander. The pressure was too much. He knew that, sooner or later, they will just crash his skull with a stone. He needed a plan. He needed a way to survive (both him and them!), without ruining it all. Without having to look the fool he knew he was.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PhantomJS 1.9.6 vs 1.9.7: what went wrong?</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2014/01/phantomjs_196vs197" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PhantomJS 1.9.6 vs 1.9.7: what went wrong?" /><published>2014-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2014/01/phantomjs_196vs197</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2014/01/phantomjs_196vs197"><![CDATA[<p><em>tl;dr;</em> Latest <strong>stable</strong> release of PhantomJS is <strong>1.9.7</strong>, and you
should probably go and <a href="http://phantomjs.org/download.html">download it</a>.
It contains <a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/releases/tag/1.1.0">GhostDriver 1.1.0 “Banquo”</a>,
and that’s it.</p>

<p>1.9.6, released not more than 2 weeks ago (1 week?), was a <em>coordination went wrong</em>
and I take part of the responsibility for it. Just discard that release.</p>

<h1 id="whats-the-long-story">What’s the long story?</h1>
<p>So, for a few days I was helping with testing and refining the
<a href="https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/pull/11535">new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cookiejar</code> module (#11535)</a>
for PhantomJS that <a href="https://github.com/jtrollinson">Joseph Rollinson (jtrollinson)</a>
contributed.
I’m very interested in this module because it allows to instantiate <strong>multiple
Cookie Jar objects</strong> instead of having all the WebPage object use the same jar.
Such feature would allow GhostDriver to finally support
<a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/issues/170">Session Isolation (#170)</a>, a long
overdue feature.</p>

<p><a href="http://ivandemarino.me/2014/01/ghostdriver-1-1-0-codename-banquo/">I had just released GhostDriver 1.1.0</a>,
and so I was pretty much all setup to do an extra release.
Having that feature supported would make PhantomJS/GhostDriver play better with
Selenium Grid, allowing to register more than 1 session against one browser
process instance.</p>

<p>So, once the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cookijar</code> thing was merged, I cut
<a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/releases/tag/1.1.1">GhostDriver 1.1.1 “Okiku”</a>
and promptly made
<a href="https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/pull/11893">a PR against PhantomJS to merge that in</a>.</p>

<p><a href="github.com/ariya">Ariya</a> was so kind to wait for me to do that and cut a <strong>minor</strong> release of
PhantomJS: in his intention <em>just bugfixes and latest GhostDriver</em>.
Little he knew that latest GhostDriver depended on the new <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cookiejar</code> feature.</p>

<p>So, when he prepared the release branch (by <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git cherry-pick</code>-ing), left out
the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cookiejar</code> module, but included GhostDriver 1.1.1.</p>

<p>Result? KA-BOOM!</p>

<div class="img">
    <img src="http://strangesounds.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/KA-BOOM-1.jpg" alt="KA-BOOM!" />
</div>

<h1 id="lesson-learned">Lesson Learned</h1>
<p>Next time I decide to add support to a major feature (even if it’s not in my
direct project but the one I’m based upon), I should increase the
<strong>minor version number</strong> or even the <strong>major</strong> (depending on the case).</p>

<p>If I had done that, Ariya would have known that
<em>it wasn’t just a minor fix in GhostDriver</em>,
and this mess would have been avoided.</p>

<p>Happy <em>Ghosting</em>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ivan De Marino</name></author><category term="ghostdriver" /><category term="phantomjs" /><category term="release" /><category term="changes" /><category term="git" /><category term="misunderstanding" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[tl;dr; Latest stable release of PhantomJS is 1.9.7, and you should probably go and download it. It contains GhostDriver 1.1.0 “Banquo”, and that’s it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GhostDriver 1.1.0: codename “Banquo”</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2014/01/ghostdriver-1-1-0-codename-banquo" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GhostDriver 1.1.0: codename “Banquo”" /><published>2014-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2014/01/ghostdriver-1-1-0-codename-banquo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2014/01/ghostdriver-1-1-0-codename-banquo"><![CDATA[<p>It’s long overdue. Last time I have cut a release of GhostDriver
(<a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/releases/tag/1.0.4">1.0.4</a>)
was… July 2013.
And <a href="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/08/10/GhostDriver-1-0-4-blog-migration-and-blogging-too-little/">blogged about it</a>
only in August!!!
I gotta take a look at my GitHub commits over the 2013: something tells me that
<em>year-in-commits</em> nicely overlaps with my eventful 2013.
But let’s try to stay on topic.</p>

<p>So, <a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/releases/tag/1.1.0">GhostDriver 1.1.0</a>,
codename <em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banquo">“Banquo”</a></em>.
This time the codename was picked by my wife - fitting, given how important she
has become this year for Leonardo and Me.</p>

<p>I know, I keep going off topic. Sorry…</p>

<p>As I’m writing, this new version hasn’t been imported into PhantomJS yet,
but it will be very soon. Definitely before next release of PhantomJS. And please,
don’t ask me about that - there is the
<a href="https://groups.google.com/d/forum/phantomjs">PhantomJS Google Group</a>
for this kind of questions (I have
<a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/phantomjs/ouFiiB1UoLw">just opened a discussion</a>
about this).</p>

<h1 id="whats-new-in-110">What’s new in 1.1.0</h1>

<p>For a complete, up-to-date list of changes in the releases of
GhostDriver, please DO take a look at the
<a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">CHANGELOG</code></a>.</p>

<p>Here is a <em>cut&amp;paste</em> for 1.1.0:</p>

<ul>
  <li>ENHANCEMENT #293: Import Selenium 2.39.0 WebDriver Atoms</li>
  <li>ENHANCEMENT: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/maximize</code> window will set the window size to 1336x768,
currently most common resolution online (see <a href="http://gs.statcounter.com/#resolution-ww-monthly-201307-201312">statcounter</a>)</li>
  <li>ENHANCEMENT #275: <strong>Implemented Browser and Network (HAR) Logging types</strong></li>
  <li>FIXED #284: Attempt to wait for Page to Load if input causes form submit</li>
  <li>FIXED #291: Throw exception when attempting to set invalid timeout value</li>
  <li>FIXED #259: Fix issue regarding mouse clicks</li>
  <li>ENHANCEMENT #290: Enabled support for “Keep Alive” HTTP connections</li>
  <li>ENHANCEMENT #262: <strong>Allow access to PhantomJS API from WebDriver (Driver part)</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>As you might have noticed, I have highlighted 2 entries above…</p>

<h2 id="browser-and-network-har-logging">Browser and Network (HAR) Logging</h2>

<p>One <em>difficulty</em> of working with an headless browser is: there is no
direct way to look at the browser and try to understand what it’s doing. It’s
pretty much a black-box and debugging your tests against it might be hard.</p>

<p>Logging was already implemented, but the only way to grab the output was via
<strong>standard output/error redirect</strong>. Not always suitable for the client-server
architecture of WebDriver.</p>

<p>The WebDriver WireProtocol defines a
<a href="https://code.google.com/p/selenium/wiki/JsonWireProtocol#/session/:sessionId/log">set of API to access LOGs</a>
of different type.
The <em>logtype</em> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">client</code> is implemented by the binding. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">driver</code> should
provide a view into the <em>inner guts</em> of the WebDriver implementation. The
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">browser</code> essentially is the <em>console</em> of the browser. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">server</code>… I’m
not sure.
In GhostDriver 1.1.0 we have added support for 2: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">browser</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">har</code>.</p>

<p><em>HAR???</em> Yes, <a href="http://www.softwareishard.com/blog/har-12-spec/">HAR - HTTP Archive</a>.
While I explained already the browser log-type, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">har</code> will return a single-entry
log, with the HAR of the current webpage, since the first load (it’s cleared
at every <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">unload</code> event).</p>

<p>Support for the other logtypes might come in the future (the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">driver</code> type should
be simple enough).</p>

<p>A great <strong>THANK YOU</strong> goes to <a href="https://github.com/torinaki">Dmitry Balabka (torinaki)</a>
and <a href="https://github.com/wgroeneveld">Wouter Groeneveld (wgroeneveld)</a> for their
key contributions. <em>Keep it coming guys!</em></p>

<h2 id="access-to-phantomjs-api">Access to PhantomJS API</h2>

<p>This feature that has been requested SO MANY FREAKING TIMES!!!</p>

<p>PhantomJS has <a href="https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/wiki/API-Reference">a rich set of API</a>
to control and tune the internal WebKit core.
Access to the plethora of API that PhantomJS has was always high, since the
beginning of the GhostDriver project.</p>

<p>While some see GhostDriver/PhantomJS as <em>just</em> a WebDriver implementation against
a non-production browser, others see this as a way to easily control PhantomJS
from another software.
The issue was that the WebDriver Protocol is <em>tuned</em> for a specific scenario: emulate
user interaction with a browser. PhantomJS is a bit less of a browser, and more
of a <strong>scriptable browser engine</strong>. And it’s very useful in scenarios also not
strictly related to testing and user interaction.</p>

<p>This API allows to send a string of JavaScript, written for PhantomJS, and be
interpreted within the context of a WebDriver Page. In other words, for the given
script the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">this</code> variable is initialized to be the current Page.</p>

<p>The format of this <em>WebDriver Protocol Extension</em>:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>HTTP POST /session/:id/phantom/execute
{
    "script"    : SCRIPT_SCRIPT
    "args"      : [ARRAY_OF_JS_BASIC_TYPES]
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>To see an example use of this API, check out
<a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/blob/master/test/java/src/test/java/ghostdriver/PhantomJSCommandTest.java">this example</a>.</p>

<p>This new API was <strong>entirely developed</strong> by
<a href="https://github.com/watsonmw">Mark Watson (watsonmw)</a>,
ex-colleague of mine at
<a href="http://ivandemarino.me/2011/12/14/Crossing-the-pond/">Neustar</a>
and awesome chap.</p>

<h1 id="what-do-i-have-left-to-do">What do I have left to do</h1>

<p>As I write this, I still have to finish up a couple of tasks to consider 1.1.0
fully released:</p>

<ul>
  <li><del>Commit 1.1.0 Java Bindings’s JAR to the Selenium repository</del>
<a href="https://code.google.com/p/selenium/source/detail?r=6146f3a5bec6bd28747e91a07cacd75a3db589f2">DONE</a></li>
  <li><del>Import 1.1.0 into PhantomJS</del>
<a href="https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/pull/11877">DONE</a></li>
  <li><del>Tag 1.1.0 on the repository</del>
<a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/releases/tag/1.1.0">DONE</a></li>
</ul>

<p>I could have waited for those tasks to be complete… but I felt like this
was overdue and I wanted to share a <em>status report</em> as soon as I could.</p>

<p>Also, it gives me <em>closure</em> for this blog post.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ivan De Marino</name></author><category term="ghostdriver" /><category term="phantomjs" /><category term="release" /><category term="changes" /><category term="info" /><category term="banquo" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s long overdue. Last time I have cut a release of GhostDriver (1.0.4) was… July 2013. And blogged about it only in August!!! I gotta take a look at my GitHub commits over the 2013: something tells me that year-in-commits nicely overlaps with my eventful 2013. But let’s try to stay on topic.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oldboy: 10 years later</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/12/oldboy-10-years-later" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oldboy: 10 years later" /><published>2013-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2013-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2013/12/oldboy-10-years-later</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/12/oldboy-10-years-later"><![CDATA[<p>It was 10 years ago. A night just like this one. Winter. Everyone in the house
was asleep. Well, Leonardo isn’t really sleeping right now but you get the idea.
I was alone in the kitchen. Alone with the TV, an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.avi</code> file and an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.srt</code> file.</p>

<p>I had just started watching movies in foreign language and during the week I had
stumbled upon <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0364569/">Old Boy</a>.
I wasn’t really in the mode of staying up late, but something made me.</p>

<div class="img">
    <img src="/img/oldboy-poster-korean.jpg" alt="Oldboy (2003)" />
    <span>Oldboy (Korean poster)</span>
</div>

<p>The title was in English: how was I supposed to know it was a movie from
South Korea? I know, I was <em>very naïve</em>.</p>

<p>I remember being captured very quickly by the story. It was intriguing, cruel,
nightmare-ish. Just the kind of stuff that tingles me. The main actor,
<a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0158856/">Min-sik Choi</a>,
looked a lot like <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000329/">Jackie Chan</a>,
but much better at acting.</p>

<p>I just finished watching it again. Now I got a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">.mkv</code>, and the subtitles are a
track in it, but the greatness of this movie comes back to mind.</p>

<p><strong>Luckly I had almost entirely forgotten the story, so I have enjoyed it all over
again</strong>. But it’s funny: 10 years later you see new details - you notice new scenes,
new details you had missed, new characters even. I had totally forgot about the
way he gets released and the first guy with the dog that
he meets once he is back in the world.</p>

<p>Same exact movie: what is changed is me. In 10 years SO MUCH has changed.
10 years ago I had not met yet my lovely wife. I knew I wanted to leave the
limiting life of the south of Italy, but I didn’t know I could actually do it.
I didn’t know that the next time me and this movie would meet,
I’d be living a completely new life.
With a beautiful wife and a beautiful son - my own little family that
is just starting.</p>

<p>Every New Year’s Eve I look back at the year, make a mental list of what changed,
<em>“where am I now”</em>. I enjoy thinking that, next year, I’ll be somewhere else
again with my life. <em>How exciting!</em></p>

<p>Maybe in 10 years, 2023, I should find again this long lost friend of a movie,
and watch it again. What the hell! I will definitely do that. Let’s just hope
I don’t change too much and forget to do it.</p>

<p>Maybe in 10 years, my son will join me. Well, he will be 10 and this movie
will be probably too <em>“gruesome”</em> for him - let’s say he will have to wait 20
years instead…</p>

<p><strong>Time</strong>. You bastard. How do you go so fast?</p>

<h1 id="ps">P.S.</h1>

<p>Yes, I know that
<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1321511/">Spike Lee’s “new” Oldboy</a>
has just been released, but that’s an almost total coincidence.
I’m going to eventually watch this <em>USA edition</em>, but I don’t expect it to make
me happy - remakes are usually badly executed.
Still, the actors involved are very good so I don’t expect to be disappointed either.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ivan De Marino</name></author><category term="oldboy" /><category term="movie" /><category term="south korea" /><category term="personal" /><category term="growth" /><category term="life" /><category term="change" /><category term="italy" /><category term="uk" /><category term="night" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was 10 years ago. A night just like this one. Winter. Everyone in the house was asleep. Well, Leonardo isn’t really sleeping right now but you get the idea. I was alone in the kitchen. Alone with the TV, an .avi file and an .srt file.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RESETtling…</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/11/resettling" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RESETtling…" /><published>2013-11-30T23:36:12+00:00</published><updated>2013-11-30T23:36:12+00:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2013/11/resettling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/11/resettling"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Puff, Pant!</strong> THAT was not easy! But finally, “normality” seems not too far
away.</p>

<p>Many things have happened in the recent months: we got <strong>married</strong>; I helped my
lovely wife with the <strong>pregnancy</strong> (well, she did all the hard work); and, on the
7th of November, we have became parents of this <strong>beauty</strong>:</p>

<div class="img">
<img src="/img/leo.png" alt="Leonardo Antonio DE MARINO-SIMOLA" />
<span>Leonardo Antonio DE MARINO-SIMOLA</span>
</div>

<p>Now, we have to slowly learn to live our new life <strong>together</strong>: while we learn
how to be parents, Leonardo will be learning how to be a baby. What now looks
like a difficult, consuming and intense task (ask me how much we sleep
at night!), will at some point become “daily routine”.
<em>A sweeter routine with Leo at the center of it all!</em></p>

<p>It is a full <strong>RESET</strong> to which we need to <strong>SETTLE</strong>. A <strong>RESETTLE</strong>.</p>

<p>A new life,
with many unknowns to uncover, but also the will and need to be as united and as
strong - actually, even more. But love seems to be our great strength, and
Alessandra and I are quite good at <em>teamwork</em>.</p>

<h1 id="night-sleep-a-memory-of-the-past">Night sleep: a memory of the past</h1>

<p>Well, as EVERYONE warned us, sleeping with a newborn baby is like trying to play
retro videogames: you ALWAYS want to do, but never manage to.</p>

<p>Leonardo is a very unstable sleeper so far, and he seems to like to be more
active during the night: maybe a good skill if he decides to join me in the
<em>craft of programming</em>, but for now it’s just an energy drain (for us!).
A drain that transforms into a sweet smile once you see his eyes looking at you.
You are tired, you are exhausted but, somehow, his puffy cheeks make
everything perfect.</p>

<p>One thing that seems to work is carrying him around, while I rock him and tell
him all sort of <em>stuff</em>, just from the top of my head.
I think I have already talked him into becoming a software developer: he hasn’t
disagreed, so I assume he is OK with it :-P .</p>

<h1 id="time-for-ourselves">Time for ourselves?</h1>

<p>This is close to <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">0</code> for now. Either as a couple, or on our own, time to do
stuff by yourself seems a very hard thing to achieve. But I’m sure it will get
better: myself I’m still a night-worker, so with his sleeping becoming more
regular, working a bit on <strong>opensource</strong> or playing videogames will be
eventually possible.</p>

<h2 id="blog-migration-finished">Blog migration finished!</h2>

<p>Talking of having no time to do stuff, while it seemed quite impossible,
I have indeed managed to complete
the blog migration! It took a while to do
the different bits, and I still have stuff to work on, but I’m now serving this
from <a href="http://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>
using <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> to generate the static HTML/CSS/JS.
Much happier: I can move to any other hosting in a matter of hours. I don’t
even know why I was bothering to use non-static content for
blogging/personal site.</p>

<p>If interested, the repository with all the source code (posts +
Jekyll plugins) can be found at my
<a href="https://github.com/detro/detro.github.io/tree/source">detro/detro.github.io “source” branch</a>.</p>

<h1 id="resume-blogging">Resume blogging</h1>

<p>Migrating the blog means also producing more content, right?
Well, this is a first attempt. Not a great one, I admit -
I find quite difficult to come up with things to say, when my brain it’s
affected by sleep deprivation.
But I have a TODO list on my whiteboard of things I want to talk about:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Bought and still setting up a <a href="http://www8.hp.com/uk/en/products/proliant-servers/product-detail.html?oid=5336624#!tab=features">N54L</a>
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ZFS">ZFS</a> NAS at home: I think some of the
decisions I have taken so far in the configuration process are worth sharing</li>
  <li>An update on the status of the
<a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver">GhostDriver</a> and
<a href="http://phantomjs.org">PhantomJS</a> projects</li>
  <li>A satiric bible-related story that I want to publish (very short and
quite offensive :P)</li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/detro/sulfur">Sulfur</a>, that I haven’t introduced
nor documented properly <em>yet</em>: it’s a tiny Java library that provides a level
of abstraction over <a href="http://www.seleniumhq.org/">Selenium</a></li>
  <li>2013 is the year I read the most in my life:
<a href="http://www.georgerrmartin.com/">George R.R. Martin</a> and
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arthur_Conan_Doyle">Arthur Conan Doyle</a>
<em>in primis</em></li>
  <li>I’m leaving <a href="http://www.amazondcl.com/">Amazon AIV ADCL</a></li>
  <li>Algorithms that I have re-studied and coded examples of</li>
</ol>

<h1 id="catching-up-on-personal-projects">Catching up on personal projects</h1>

<p>I have been quite far from <a href="http://www.seleniumhq.org/">Selenium</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver">GhostDriver</a> and
<a href="http://phantomjs.org">PhantomJS</a>. Partially is my fault (I did spend some time
playing <em>GTA V</em> before Leonardo was here), but mostly is because of all the
above.</p>

<p>While I don’t really have a fully up-to-date picture of what’s happening with
PhantomJS, I know that
<a href="https://github.com/Vitallium/phantomjs-qt5">Vitallium is working on the porting to Qt5</a>.
That is a very exciting perspective, and the project looks like it has a
brilliant future ahead.</p>

<p>Also, the <a href="http://qt-project.org/">Qt-Project</a> is
<a href="http://blog.qt.digia.com/blog/2013/06/25/experimenting-with-chromium-and-qt/">moving Chromium/Blink</a>:
this means that PhantomJS architecture will have to change sensibly, the core
will be based on a more <em>commercial</em> browser and, most importantly, I believe
a full API compatibility break would be a given. <em>Why is that good?</em> Because
we could apply all we learned from developing PhantomJS so far, and do a better
job in many areas.</p>

<h2 id="quick-note-about-ghostdriver">Quick note about GhostDriver</h2>

<p>GhostDriver has received some love (aka <em>Pull Requests</em>). I have worked to
integrate them into an upcoming <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1.1.0</code>, but I think there are other more
pressing improvements to do, before considering a release.</p>

<p>And, if you really want to, you can still check out the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">master</code> branch
and run it inside latest PhantomJS. So, I don’t feel too much pressure to
package a full release.</p>

<p><em>That’s all for now.</em></p>

<p><strong>P.S.</strong> I still haven’t told you what’s my next job, have I? :)</p>]]></content><author><name>Ivan De Marino</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="leonardo" /><category term="life" /><category term="reset" /><category term="settling" /><category term="blogging" /><category term="opensource" /><category term="ghostdriver" /><category term="phantomjs" /><category term="job" /><category term="career" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Puff, Pant! THAT was not easy! But finally, “normality” seems not too far away.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GhostDriver 1.0.4, blog migration and blogging too little</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/08/10/GhostDriver-1-0-4-blog-migration-and-blogging-too-little" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GhostDriver 1.0.4, blog migration and blogging too little" /><published>2013-08-09T16:03:47+01:00</published><updated>2013-08-09T16:03:47+01:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2013/08/10/ghostdriver-1-0-4-blog-migration-and-blogging-too-little</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/08/10/GhostDriver-1-0-4-blog-migration-and-blogging-too-little"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, I’m not blogging enough.
Yes, it’s a shame that the world can’t read my terrible English on a more regular basis.
Yes, I’m lazy.</p>

<p>Well, here is a quick update for the few eager souls I have let down.</p>

<h3 id="ghostdriver">GhostDriver</h3>

<p>I have release <a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/releases/tag/1.0.4">GhostDriver 1.0.4 - “Arghan Div”</a>. It should be released in the <a href="https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/issues/11452">upcoming PhantomJS 1.9.2</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
<img src="http://placehold.it/600x150/eee/500&amp;text=1.0.4" />
</div>

<p>The code has been merged already into <a href="https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs/commit/73bb56084028e1ee902bfedb8bd0443b337c7578">PhantomJS master branch</a> so, if you are really keen on putting your hands on it, just do a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">./build.sh</code> of that branch.</p>

<h3 id="blog-migration">Blog migration</h3>

<p>I’m planning to abandon <a href="https://github.com/detro/bloggart">my fork of Bloggart</a>. I have written a “backupper” that uses Node.JS to download and save locally all the Pages and Posts stored in it. If you use Bloggart and want to “leave” as well, look in <a href="https://github.com/detro/bloggart/tree/blogivandemarinome-configuration/backup">here</a>.</p>

<p>I want to move to a static generated, file stored blog. I initially thought about building it myself, but then I realised I have no time so I’m going to use <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>. First tests look promising. I hope I’ll get around to do it. And I want to use GitHub Pages to host it.</p>

<p>I’ll probably have to make sure URLs are redirected properly, as I don’t know how much of my current hostname structure I can use on GitHub pages.</p>

<h3 id="blogging-too-little">Blogging too little</h3>

<p>One reason to migrate is that I think I’ll write more if I can dump my thoughts into text file and do a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git push</code>: loading a URL to the Admin interface of this blog and typing in a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">textarea</code> is sort of difficult nowdays.</p>

<p>So that might make me blog more. Or not. I don’t know. Will see.</p>

<p>Cheers.</p>]]></content><author><name>detro</name></author><category term="github" /><category term="phantomjs" /><category term="blog" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="migration" /><category term="release" /><category term="bloggart" /><category term="ghostdriver" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yes, I’m not blogging enough. Yes, it’s a shame that the world can’t read my terrible English on a more regular basis. Yes, I’m lazy. Well, here is a quick update for the few eager souls I have let down. GhostDriver I have release GhostDriver 1.0.4 - “Arghan Div”. It should be released in the upcoming PhantomJS 1.9.2. The code has been merged already into PhantomJS master branch so, if you are really keen on putting your hands on it, just do a ./build.sh of that branch. Blog migration I’m planning to abandon my fork of Bloggart. I have written a “backupper” that uses Node.JS to download and save locally all the Pages and Posts stored in it. If you use Bloggart and want to “leave” as well, look in here. I want to move to a static generated, file stored blog. I initially thought about building it myself, but then I realised I have no time so I’m going to use Jekyll. First tests look promising. I hope I’ll get around to do it. And I want to use GitHub Pages to host it. I’ll probably have to make sure URLs are redirected properly, as I don’t know how much of my current hostname structure I can use on GitHub pages. Blogging too little One reason to migrate is that I think I’ll write more if I can dump my thoughts into text file and do a git push: loading a URL to the Admin interface of this blog and typing in a textarea is sort of difficult nowdays. So that might make me blog more. Or not. I don’t know. Will see. Cheers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’m off. See you in 2 weeks.</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/03/29/I-m-off-See-you-in-2-weeks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’m off. See you in 2 weeks." /><published>2013-03-28T17:53:06+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-28T17:53:06+00:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2013/03/29/i-m-off-see-you-in-2-weeks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/03/29/I-m-off-See-you-in-2-weeks"><![CDATA[<p>This message is for the few souls that care. This is for the few people that maybe are waiting for me to fix/implement stuff on <a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver">GhostDriver</a> or <a href="https://github.com/ariya/phantomjs">PhantomJS</a> (for the latter you have coverage, as the team on that is rich of geniuses - so you won’t miss my average-hood).</p>

<p>I’m <strong>getting married</strong> (crazy, right?) and will be mostly off-line. I should be back from the second week of April.</p>

<div class="img">
<img src="http://blog.fashionwindows.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/exchanging_rings.jpg" />
</div>

<p>Surely there will be the usual <em>casual-tweet</em> but nothing major.</p>

<p>See ya!</p>]]></content><author><name>detro</name></author><category term="phantomjs" /><category term="personal" /><category term="off-line" /><category term="marriage" /><category term="wedding" /><category term="ghostdriver" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This message is for the few souls that care. This is for the few people that maybe are waiting for me to fix/implement stuff on GhostDriver or PhantomJS (for the latter you have coverage, as the team on that is rich of geniuses - so you won’t miss my average-hood). I’m getting married (crazy, right?) and will be mostly off-line. I should be back from the second week of April. Surely there will be the usual casual-tweet but nothing major. See ya!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GhostDriver 1.0.3 is out!</title><link href="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/03/19/GhostDriver-1-0-3-is-out" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GhostDriver 1.0.3 is out!" /><published>2013-03-18T18:25:19+00:00</published><updated>2013-03-18T18:25:19+00:00</updated><id>http://ivandemarino.me/2013/03/19/updated-phantomjs-1-9-0-ghostdriver-1-0-3-is-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ivandemarino.me/2013/03/19/GhostDriver-1-0-3-is-out"><![CDATA[<p>After few months of endless nights trying to figure out what I screwed up and where, I’m finally happy (enough) to release <strong>GhostDriver 1.0.3</strong> into the wild.</p>

<p>This release is an <em>hardening release</em>: this means that it’s focused on bug-fixing and very little new features have been added.</p>

<p><strong>GhostDriver 1.0.3</strong> <del>will be part of the upcoming <strong>PhantomJS 1.9</strong> release, do in few days</del> is now part of <strong>PhantomJS 1.9.0</strong>, and you can download binaries for various platform from <a href="https://code.google.com/p/phantomjs/downloads/list">https://code.google.com/p/phantomjs/downloads/list</a>.</p>

<div class="img">
<img src="http://dummyimage.com/500x220/383b38/00ff00.png&amp;text=1.0.3" />
</div>
<p>If you want to know what made it for the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1.0.3</code> cut, take a look at the <a href="https://github.com/detro/ghostdriver/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md">Changelog</a>.</p>

<p>I apologise in advance for whom have seen his “pet issue” not being implemented/fixed/addressed for this release, but it’s only one of me.</p>

<p>I’d like to take the time to thank the few brave souls that have contributed to this release with their code. In chronological contribution order:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/garyd203">garyd203</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/c089">Christoph Neuroth</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/nathandace">Nathan Dace</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/loduis">Loduis Madariaga Barrios</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/benmccann">Ben McCann</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Thanks guys! <em>Keep being awesome!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>detro</name></author><category term="webdriver" /><category term="contributors" /><category term="phantomjs" /><category term="1.0.3" /><category term="release" /><category term="1.9.0" /><category term="ghostdriver" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After few months of endless nights trying to figure out what I screwed up and where, I’m finally happy (enough) to release GhostDriver 1.0.3 into the wild. This release is an hardening release: this means that it’s focused on bug-fixing and very little new features have been added. GhostDriver 1.0.3 will be part of the upcoming PhantomJS 1.9 release, do in few days is now part of PhantomJS 1.9.0, and you can download binaries for various platform from https://code.google.com/p/phantomjs/downloads/list. If you want to know what made it for the 1.0.3 cut, take a look at the Changelog. I apologise in advance for whom have seen his “pet issue” not being implemented/fixed/addressed for this release, but it’s only one of me. I’d like to take the time to thank the few brave souls that have contributed to this release with their code. In chronological contribution order: garyd203 Christoph Neuroth Nathan Dace Loduis Madariaga Barrios Ben McCann Thanks guys! Keep being awesome!]]></summary></entry></feed>